(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-14T09:30:45.176222",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
歌えませーん！
I can't sing!
みんな 今日は何の日か知ってる？
Everyone, do you know what day today is?
分かるよね？
You know, right?
そう！ シオンの誕生日！
That's right! It's Shion's birthday!
今日はなんと！
Today, amazingly...
シオンのやってみたいことやっちゃおー！
Let's do all the things Shion wants to try!
というわけで、せっかくの誕生日なので、
So, since it's her birthday,
シオンがめちゃくちゃやりたいことを詰め込む旅に行こうと思います！
we're going on a trip packed with
all the things Shion wants to do!
イェーイ！
Yay!
人生初めての体験や独占のなども あるからついてきてね！
There will be first-time life experiences
and exclusive things, so follow along!
じゃあ、出発！
Well then, let's set off!
おはようございま～す
Good morning!
いや、マジで朝早よぉ～
Man, it's seriously early in the morning~
今日はシオンさんが1日にやりたい事を詰め込んでるんで...
Today, you've packed a whole day's worth
of things you want to do...
うん！
Yeah!
行きましょ！
Let's go!
はい！！
Okay!!
朝ごはんはシオンさんが好きな昆布おにぎりです
For breakfast, it's your favorite kelp rice ball.
ありがとうございます！ 買ってきてくださって。
Thank you so much for buying it for me.
はい。
Yes.
じゃあ...行きますか！！
Well then... shall we get going!!
行きましょ！
Let's go!
しゅっぱ～つ！！
Let's set off!!
都内から車に揺られること1時間半、
Being rocked in a car from Tokyo for an hour and a half,
シオンのやってみたいことやっちゃお、最初にたどり着き...
Shion's "Let's do what I want to try" first arrived at...
たのは？
What was that?
はい！というわけでやってきました〜！
Yay! So we've arrived~!
ここはどこでしょう！
Where do you think we are?
栃木県で〜す！！
It's Tochigi Prefecture!!
いえ〜い！！
Yay!!
来ましたね栃木県。
We made it to Tochigi.
ねぇ、来ましたねぇ〜
Yeah, we really did~
シオンさん栃木県って来たことありますか？
Shion-san, have you ever been to Tochigi?
いや、来たことないですね…
Nope, never been here...
初栃木。
First time in Tochigi.
はい、初栃木、見える感じま…
Yep, first Tochigi, from what I can see...
かなり草。
Lots of grass.
栃木県はなんかイチゴが美味しいとか
Tochigi is known for delicious strawberries, right?
宇都宮の餃子とかが有名ですね
And Utsunomiya gyoza is famous, too.
そうなんだ〜！
Is that right~!
までもこの辺にはなさそうですけど
But there doesn't seem to be any around here...
いや、ちょっと草ですね
Hehe, just grass here.
そんな栃木県でシオンさんがやってみたいことはなんですか！？
In such Tochigi Prefecture, what would you like to try, Shion-san!?
スカイダイビングで〜す！！
Skydiving!!
最初のやってみたいことやっちゃおっわスカイダイビング！
Let's do our first wish: skydiving!
ご協力いただいたのはスカイダイブ藤岡さん！
Special thanks to Skydive Fujioka!
飛行機に乗って登っていくのはこんなに高いところ！
Riding the plane up to such a high place!
大丈夫！？
Are you okay!?
なんでスカイダイビングなんですか？
Why skydiving?
遊園地のジェットコースターとかめっちゃ好きなんですよ。
I really like amusement park roller coasters and stuff.
てことは高ければ高いほど楽しいかなと思って
So I figured the higher it is, the more fun it'll be.
いや一番高そうじゃないですかスカイダイビングが
And skydiving seems like the highest one out there!
そっすね。
That's true.
どの位の高さだと思います？
How high do you think it is?
えぇ〜！ちょっとホントにわかんないなぁ…
Eek! I honestly have no idea...
シオンさん身長何cmですか？
Shion-san, how tall are you?
はいはいはい。
Yes, yes, yes.
145cm
145 cm.
シオンさんが500人いたら725m
If there were 500 Shions, that's 725 meters!
はい。でもスカイツリーって600なんとかメートルですよね？
Yes. But Tokyo Skytree is around 600-something meters, right?
そうですね。
That's right.
え、いいんじゃないですか！？けっこう、スカイツリーくらいの高さから飛ぶかな？って感じですか
Eh, isn't that good!? Like, jumping from about Skytree's height?
スカイツリー1本で良いですか？
Is one Skytree enough?
2本！！2本で
Two!! Two of them!
正解は…スカイツリー
The correct answer is... six Skytrees—
6本分の3800mです！
3,800 meters!
えぇーー！！シオンさんで言うと2600シオン
Whoa!! In terms of Shions, that's 2,600 Shions!
わかんないwww
Makes no sense www
富士山一個分
One whole Mt. Fuji!
そう言われるとすごいっすね…
Put that way, that's amazing...
富士山の上から飛ぶイメージ
The image of jumping from the top of Mt. Fuji.
えぇーー！！ドキドキしますねぇ…ドキドキして来ました
Whoa!! I'm getting nervous... I've gotten nervous!
してきた！楽しみ！じゃあちょっと実際向かってみましょうか。はい！行きましょう！
I have! I'm excited! Well then, let's actually head over there. Yeah! Let's go!
その前にスカイダイビングを安全に楽しむためのレクチャーを受けないとね！
Before that, we need to take a lecture to enjoy skydiving safely!
空中での正しい姿勢や着陸方法をインストラクターさんから学んで
Learn proper posture in the air and landing methods from the instructor,
いざ搭乗開始
and now, boarding begins!
やばいやばい
Oh no, oh no
怖いですか？
Are you scared?
やばい
Scary
えぇ〜
Eek~
いやまだ…この音が怖いですね
No, not yet... The sound is scary.
歯医者さんくらい怖い
Scary like a dentist.
飛行機乗るの何回目ですか？
How many times have you been on a plane?
乗ったことないです！
Never been on one!
怖いんでシオンさん先飛んでください
It's scary, so Shion-san, please jump first.
ヤです
No way.
ジャンケンして決めますか？
Shall we decide with rock-paper-scissors?
ヤです
No way.
うおおおおおおおおおおおおお
Uwaaaaaaaaaaaah...
音やばい！！
The sound is crazy!!
飛んでんじゃない？
Aren't we flying?
飛んだぁー！！
We're flying!!
やったぁ…
Yay...
大丈夫！？ww
Are you okay!? ww
うははwww 大丈夫ダヨー きっと…
Uhaha www It'll be fine, I'm sure...
まだ上がってますよ…？うん。まだ上がって
We're still going up...? Yeah. Still going up—
雲の中だ…
We're in the clouds...
ホントだぁー！！
For real!!
富士山？
Mt. Fuji?
シオンさん！？
Shion-san!?
はいっ、はいはい
Yes, yes yes.
開いた〜！
It opened~!
あっやばいwwww
Ah, oh no wwww
がんばれ〜w
Good luck~ w
キャァァァァァ！！ひゃアヤバwwww
Kyaaaaaaa!! Hyaaa dangerous wwww
がんばれー！
Good luck!
ひゃぁぁぁぁぁぁ…
Hyaaaaaaa...
ヤバイ！！ヤバイ！！待ってぇ↑待って…
No way!! No way!! Wait↑ Wait...
どうするの…！？
What should I do...!?
いやちょっと…
Well, hold on...
言葉にならないwww
I'm speechless, lol.
死んだかと思ったw
I thought I died, lol.
死んだと思いましたよね？w
You thought you died too, right? Lol.
と思いました
I did.
呼吸できなかったもん
I couldn't even breathe!
いやそう
Exactly.
できなかったですよね
You couldn't, right? Lol.
できなかったすよね
You really couldn't!
「口開けてたら死んだ」って喋んないよとと思って
I thought, "If I open my mouth I'll die," so I had to speak!
喋りたかったんだけど
I wanted to talk, but...
喋れないwww
I couldn't even talk, lol!
どうでした？上からの景色
How was it? The view from above.
いやめっちゃキレイだったけど…
It was super pretty, but...
ちょっとホントに思ったより余裕がなかった
Honestly, I had way less composure than expected.
最高でしたね！！最高でした
It was amazing!! It was the best.
怖いと楽しいどっちが上ですか？
Which was stronger, the fear or the fun?
怖いっすね
The fear, I guess.
怖い
Scary!
でもやってみたかった事やれて…
But I got to do something I wanted...
よかった！めっちゃよかった！
It was great! So amazing!
もう1回やりたいですか？
Do you want to do it again?
いや…
No...
大満足ですよ！！ホントに良かった！いやマジで楽しかったー！！最高ー！！
I'm totally satisfied!! It was genuinely great! Seriously, that was so fun!! The best!!
いやみんなもでも是非ね、もう一度ね、1人1回くらいはやってみて欲しいですけどね。
Everyone should definitely try it out at least once themselves, you know.
ねえ！ねえ！
Right? Right?
ねぇ！ねえ！
Right! Right!
思ってないだろw
You don't mean that at all, lol!
じゃあ次に行きますか！
Well then, shall we move on?
新幹線押さえているから急いでー！！
I've booked the Shinkansen, so hurry up!!
続いてのやってみたいことやっちゃうわ
Now for the next thing we wanted to try,
大宮駅から新幹線で2時間ちょっと
just over two hours by Shinkansen from Omiya Station.
は〜い！
Here we go!
到着しました〜！ここはどこでしょ〜？
We've arrived! Where could this be?
景色見て分かる人もいるのかな？って感じですが！
I wonder if anyone can tell from the scenery!
やって来たのは富山県で〜す！！
We have come to Toyama Prefecture!!
シオンさん富山は初めてですか？
Shion-san, is this your first time in Toyama?
いや初めて来ました！
Yes, it's my first time here!
お今のところ印象どんな感じですか？
How's the impression so far?
今のところ…
So far...
海ですね…w
It's the ocean... lol.
海ですね？
The ocean?
海ですね。
It's the ocean.
今これ見て富山県どこかわかります？w
Looking at this map now, do you know where Toyama is? Lol.
あ、そういうこと？
Oh, is that so?
そうですねえ…
Let's see...
ここ…！！
Right here...!!
え…正解かんないですw
Uh... I have no idea if that's right, lol.
富山と言えばでなんか知ってるものとかありますか？
When you think of Toyama, is there anything you know about it?
え〜〜？？
Eeh~~??
なんか私が知ってるのだと『寒ブリ』とか
Well, things I know include "Kanburi" (cold yellowtail) and...
寒ブリ？寒ブリ、あのブリですか？あ、そうなんだ！
Kanburi? Kanburi, like yellowtail? Oh, really!
色々美味しいものが食べれるイメージがあります！
I have the impression you can eat all sorts of delicious food!
うーん…確かに！確かに…
Hmm... True! That's true...
カニだけに…ww
Speaking of crab... lol.
カニだけにやって来たのは新湊かに小屋。
Speaking of crab, we came to Shinminato Kani Goya.
旅行で水揚げされたばかりの旬のベニズワイガニにはその場で食べられる人気の観光スポットだそう。
It's a popular tourist spot where you can eat freshly landed seasonal snow crab on the spot.
ここですね！
This is it!
じゃあちょっと…入ってもいいのかな？
Well then... I wonder if it's okay to go in?
いらっしゃいませ〜！
Welcome!
ようこそ〜！
お邪魔しま〜す！
Excuse us!
どうぞ、お席の方へ。
Please, this way to your seats.
あ、本当ですか？失礼します。
Oh, really? Excuse us.
まずは日本海の天然のいけす富山湾で獲れた新鮮な海の幸をご賞味あれ。
First, enjoy the fresh seafood caught in Toyama Bay, Toyama's natural fish tank.
いただいちゃっていいんですか？
Can we really dig in?
食べましょう！
Let's eat!
いただきま〜す！
Itadakimasu!
いただきま〜す。
Itadakimasu.
えっ…うんまぁ…！！
Whoa... so good...!!
待って…めっちゃ美味しいんだけど。ぷるぷる！もちもち！みたいな。
Wait... this is insanely good. It's bouncy! And chewy! Like that.
え、めっちゃ柔らかい。かまぼみたいな（食感）
Huh, it's super soft. Sort of like fish cake.
エビうまw
Shrimp is so good, lol.
僕頑張って剥いた甲斐がある。
All that hard work peeling it was worth it.
めっちゃ甘いですね。
It's super sweet.
本当に。
Truly.
本当に甘い！うんま。
It's genuinely sweet! So good.
ネギ美味しい。
The green onion is delicious.
そもそもダシが美味い。めっちゃ味する。
First of all, the broth is delicious. It has so much flavor.
カキ食べますかシオンさん。
Will you eat an oyster, Shion-san?
あー、世界で一番美味いわ。え、世界で一番美味いですよ。
Ah, it's the best in the world. Uh, it's literally the best in the world.
うま…美味すぎる…
So good... too good...
うまっ…うまぁ…
So good... delicious...
ちょっと、カニこれこれ、越えられるかな…？
Wait, I wonder if this can surpass the crab...?
噛みすぎ噛みすぎw
You're biting into character too much, lol!
ですよね。んじゃ、これ超えて来れるのかなってとこですよね、カニが果たして。
Right. So the question is whether the crab can surpass this.
うまっ。
So good.
もう2個食べちゃったw
I already ate two, lol.
タラですって。
It's cod, apparently.
え、めっちゃ柔らかくないですか…？
Huh, isn't it super soft...?
食べていいですか？食べてください…！
Can I eat it? Please go ahead...!
いただきます！
Itadakimasu!
あーー…
Ahhh...
え、うま…柔らか…
Huh, so good... so soft...
とろとろじゃん。
It melts right away.
魚の皮好きなんですよねぇ。
I love fish skin, you know.
わかります。
I know, right.
え、わかります？
Huh, you know?
え、わかりますよ。
Yeah, I know.
口の中でとろける〜！
It melts in your mouth~!
セリフ過ぎたw
That sounded too scripted, lol.
いよいよ、大本命。
At last, the main event.
ベニズワイガニの登場。
The snow crab makes its appearance.
え〜美味しそう…
Wow, looks delicious...
やっぱ足が一番美味しそう。
The legs definitely look the most delicious.
「美味しそう」じゃないよ！
Don't say "looks" delicious!
「美味しい」の！
Say it "is" delicious!
あっそうですよね！！
Ah, right, of course!!
「美味しい」の！
It "is" delicious!
そうですよね！
Exactly!
もうおいしいですね
It's already delicious...
もうおいしいですよね
Right? It's already delicious.
ですよね
Right?
こうなってる
Like this?
どのくらいになったら食べるとか…
At what point should we eat it?
もう茹で上がってるから、すぐ食べれるけど
If you just want to eat it, it's already boiled,
すぐ食べれるけど、でももうちょっと…
so you can eat it right away, but...
ちょっとしみるっていうことですよね
You want to let it soak a bit more, right?
美味そっ!
That looks delicious!
「美味そ」じゃなくて「美味い」んだよねぇ!
Not "delicious," but "tasty," right?
そうですよ!
That's right!
忙しい!! かわいい!
So busy! So cute!
沸いてきたんじゃないですか? でも
Isn't it boiling by now?
沸いてます?
Is it boiling?
聞いてください、カニに
Go ask the crab!
カニに…？カニに? 沸いてますか～!?
Mr. Crab, are you boiling～!?
あー…沸いてますね
Ah, it's boiling.
沸いてます、盛り上がってます
It's boiling, it's hyped up!
じゃあ私これでちょっと…
So, with this...
戦ってみます
I'll try battling it.
違うよ絶対！それじゃないよぉ～w
No way, that's definitely not it!
なんか…こう、聞いたことあるんですけどね、これで
I've heard of doing this...
熱熱熱ッwww アツアツアツアツアツ…
So hot, hot, hot!
熱い…ッ
So hot!
来たわこと！絶対勝った!!
There it is, I totally won!
マジか
Really?
ハサミだったか…
It was scissors...
ザンネン！どんまいw
Too bad, better luck next time.
はっはっはw プロだ…
Pro-level!
さすがに勝ったかぁw
I actually won, huh?
これもいけるなこれ、反対からも切るか
Shall I cut it from the other side too?
食べてくださいよ、シオンさん
Go ahead and eat, Shion-san.
今からでも？遅くない？
Even from now? It's not too late?
いただきまーす!!
Itadakimasu!!
う～まぁ～!!!
So goood!
マジで美味い
Seriously delicious.
ふりかけにするからだよ
Because we're making it into furikake.
でもマジで美味しい、柔らかい
Seriously delicious, so tender!
これだけでも全然美味しい…！
Even just this is totally delicious...!
質が良すぎて、一口でも
The quality is so good, even a single bite...
美味さが詰まってますよ
Deliciousness packed inside!
ジャンケンしよう
Let's do janken.
これ…何ですか？これなんだと思います？
What do you think this is?
グー、グーだな、たぶんこれ
It's gu, probably.
最初はグー
First is gu...
ジャンケン…
Janken...
グー!!
Gu!!
いや…パーやん!
It's paa!
いやめちゃパーやん!
It's totally paa!
埋まってるとこめっちゃグーだったんですけど…
The buried part was totally gu, but...
めっちゃパー
It's totally paa.
一生剥けないんですけど私こう
I can never shell them...
爆発…!
Explosion!
カニ経験なさすぎて…
I have so little crab experience...
爪の中身うま…
The inside of the claw is delicious...
こことか…
Places like this...
めちゃ美味しそうですけどね…
Look super delicious...
飲み物じゃん
It's like a drink.
食べますよ
I'll eat it.
すごい
Incredible.
濃厚
Rich!
めっちゃ美味しい…濃厚
So delicious... Rich!
やっぱこれ飲み物
It really is a drink.
ここ一番好きかもしれないです
I might like this best.
ビール飲んだくなる味
A flavor that makes you want beer.
わかんないなぁ～
I don't get it.
わかんないですよねw
You don't get it, do you?
わかんない、全然わかんないこと言って
I don't get it at all.
ヤバイですよねこれ…!!
This is dangerous...!!
カニの味がする
It tastes like crab...
温泉卵の白身みたいな
Like the egg white of a hot spring egg.
食感してる
The texture is just like that.
わかりやすいなぁ、めちゃ
So easy to understand!
え、わかりやすいですよね!
Right, easy to understand!
カニ味のね
Like crab flavor.
カニ味の温泉卵の
Like crab-flavored...
ぷるぷるのとこ
That plump part.
めちゃわかりやすい
Easy to understand.
これは富山まで来た甲斐ありますね
This makes coming all the way to Toyama worth it.
ある、マジで ある
It really does.
今まで食べたカニの中で一番ですか?
Out of all the crab you've eaten so far, is this number one?
一番ですね!
It's number one!
おっ
Oh!
爪が美味い、爪が
The claw is delicious, the claw.
じゃあ、ごちそうさましますか
Well then, shall we say "gochisosamadeshita"?
はい
Yes.
せーの、ごちそうさまでした!
Ready, set, gochisosamadeshita!
じゃあ次行きますか!
Now, shall we go to the next place?
暗くなってきたしね…!
It's getting dark, too...!
ねえ
Right?
超暗いですよ、外も
It's super dark outside, too.
そうですよね
That's right, isn't it?
じゃあ行きますか
Well then, shall we go?
はい
Yes.
はーい！というわけで
Yes! And so...
みんなには見えているのでしょうか
Can everyone see it?
もう真っ暗になってね
It's pitch dark and...
夜景が見える
You can see the night view.
きれいな景色になりました
It became a beautiful scenery.
目の前は海で
In front of us is the sea,
すごい波の音が響いておりますが
and you can hear the sound of the waves.
朝からスカイダイビングして…
After skydiving from the morning...
カニ小屋で美味しいカニいっぱい食べて…
Eating lots of delicious crab at the crab hut...
富山県来てね!
Come to Toyama Prefecture!
富山でなんかまだ思い残すこととか…ないですかね?
Is there anything left you want to do in Toyama?
あるかも…!!
There might be...!
あるかもしれない!!
There might be!
海水浴!
Swimming in the ocean!
あ、海水浴ね? この…めっちゃ寒そうな…
Ah, swimming in the ocean, right?
飛び込んでみたい…？
Wanting to jump in...
じゃなくて…！
Instead of that!
今日はですね
Today is...
誕生日ということで
Since it's my birthday,
なんと6回目の誕生日だそうです
it's apparently my 6th birthday.
すごい
That's amazing.
いやすごい！本当に、いつもみんな、本当にありがとうございます!
It's amazing! Thank you all so much, as always!
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
というわけでね
So, you know,
みんなに感謝の気持ちをこめて
putting our feelings of gratitude for everyone,
お願いしま～す！！
please enjoy this!!
えええ～…！！
Whoa...!!
すご…ｗ
Amazing... lol
めっちゃ近い…！
So close...!
めちゃ真ん前だ！
Right in front of us!
この距離で見ることないですよ！
You never see them from this close!
ないですよ！
No, you don't!
なんと…花火ですね！
And behold... fireworks!
ああ、そういうこと？
Ah, is that what it is?
うわすごぉ…！
Whoa, amazing...!
めっちゃキレイ…
So pretty...
すごかった…
That was amazing...
花火打ち上げることって…ないですよね…ｗ
You don't usually launch fireworks like this... lol
聞いたことないですよ
I've never heard of such a thing.
人生でこんな事あるんだ…みたいな
Like, can things like this even happen in life...
ねぇ～！！
Right?!
うわめっちゃキレイだったぁ～…！！
Whoa, it was so pretty...!!
めっちゃ良かったですねぇ～！
It was so wonderful~!
みんなどうだったかなぁ～！めっちゃキレイだったよね？
I wonder how it was for everyone! It was super pretty, right?
ファンの方も一緒に楽しんでもらえたんじゃないですかね？
I hope the fans enjoyed it along with us too, don't you think?
うん、見れてよかった一緒に
Yeah, I'm glad we could watch it together.
どうぞこれからも皆さんよろしくお願いします！
Please continue to support us everyone!
以上で！シオンのやってみたいことやっちゃお！でした～！
That's all! That was Shion's "Let's Do What I Want to Try"!
ありがと～！
Thank you~!
さあ、シオンの初ロケいかがだったでしょうか？
Now then, how was Shion's first location shoot?
このあとはもちろんライブもやっちゃいます！
After this, of course, we're going to do a live show too!
引き続き盛り上がっていこー！
Let's keep the excitement going!
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
Stealing the spotlight with an invincible smile
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
What's your secret? It's so mysterious
抜けてるとこさえ彼女のエリア
Even your flaws are part of your charm
完璧で嘘つきな君は
You're a perfect, lying genius idol
天才的なアイドル様
Genius idol-sama!
ようやく会えたね 嬉しいね
We finally met, I'm so happy
待ち遠しくて足をバッタバタしながら
I couldn't wait and kicked my feet in excitement
今日楽しみで寝れなかったよ
I was so excited today I couldn't sleep at all
緊張なんかしてる場合じゃない
There's no time to be feeling nervous
1分1秒無駄にななんてできないさ
Not a single minute or second can go to waste
さあ 始めましょう
Now then, let's begin
君も 君も 君もお待ちどうさま
You too, you too, thank you for waiting
手を鳴らせ いらっしゃいませ
Clap your hands, welcome
「好き」が集まる場所へ ようこそ
Welcome to where all our "likes" gather
日常はクロークの中
Leave your everyday life in the cloakroom
ここに来たなら踊らにゃ損損
If you're here, you'd better dance or you'll miss out
客席が居ようが居まいが関係ない
Whether there's an audience or not doesn't matter
箱が大きいつ小さいとか気にしない
Don't care if the venue is big or small
ちゃんと見えてる 君のサイリウム
I can see it clearly, your cheering light
今ふっと吹けば飛ぶような
Like it might blow away with just a breath
小さな小さな才能だけど私を
A small, small talent, but it's all mine
私を推してくれるのなら
If you're going to support and cheer for me,
爆レスをあげる
I'll give you maximum fan service!
アナタのアイドル
I'm your idol,
サインはB♡
and your sign is B♡
あいつは俺が育てたって
You'll proudly say, "I raised that star!"
近い将来自慢してほしいよ
In the near future, showing off near and far.
どうしちゃいられない
We can't just stand still,
君と！君と！今を楽しまなきゃ
with you! with you! We've got to have fun!
引きこもりも人見知りも普段と違う顔見せてよ
Introverts and hermits, show a side that's new!
みんな兄弟調子どうだい
We're all like family, how's it going today?
なりふり構わずに そう！
Without worrying about appearances, yeah!
他人に笑われていても関係ない
Even if people laugh, it doesn't matter at all.
周りがどうとかこうとか気にしない
Don't care about what anyone else might say or call.
主張強すぎ君のサイリウムは
Your glowing lightsticks make your presence so clear,
たとえ世界が私を拒んで ひとりぼっちを感じたとしても
Even if the world rejects me and I feel all alone here,
アナタが味方でいてくれたら
As long as you stay by my side as my ally,
怖いものはないよ
There's nothing left in this world to terrify!
見てよ見てよ何が始まる
Look, look, what's about to begin?
君との物語が ああ なんて素晴らしい景色だ！
Our story together... Oh, what a wonderful scene we're in!
客席が居ようがいまいが関係ない
It doesn't matter if the audience is big or small,
会場が大きい小さいとか気にしない
No matter the venue size, we'll give it our all.
ちゃんと見えてる君のサイリウムは
I see your lightsticks clearly shining bright,
今はフーッと吹けば飛ぶような 小さな小さな才能だけど
A tiny, fragile talent that could blow away with the night,
私を 推して くれるのなら
If you're going to support and cheer for me,
アナタが 味方で いてくれたら
As long as you stay by my side as my ally,
爆レスをあげる
I'll give you maximum fan service!
アナタのアイドル
I'm your idol,
サインは B ▽
and your sign is B♡
世界で一番おひめさま そういう扱い心得てよネ
I'm the #1 princess in the world, so treat me accordingly!
その一 いつもと違う髪型に気が付くこと
Rule one: notice when my hairstyle is new.
その二 ちゃんと言うまで靴まで見ること いいね？
Rule two: look all the way to my shoes, okay too?
その三 わたしの一言には三つの言葉で返事すること わかったら右手が留守なのをなんとかして！
Rule three: reply to every word with three. And do something about my idle right hand, you see!
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or making a fuss,
キミに心から思って欲しいの「かわいい」って
I just want you to truly think I'm cute, without us!
世界で一番おひめさま 気が付いてねえねえ
I'm the #1 princess in the world, notice me, hey!
待たせるなんて論外よ
Making me wait is totally out of the way!
わたしを誰だと思ってるの もう何だか甘いものが食べたい！
Just who do you think I am? I want some sweets right away!
いますぐによ
Right this instant!
世界で一番おひめさま 気が付いてねえねえ
I'm the #1 princess in the world, notice me, hey!
待たせるなんて論外よ わたしを誰だと思ってるの
Making me wait is totally out of the way, just who do you think I am?
もう何だか甘いものが食べたい！ いますぐによ
I want some sweets right now, right this very instant!
欠点？かわいいの間違いでしょ 文句は許しませんの
Flaws? You mean adorable! No complaints are allowed!
あのね、私の話ちゃんと聞いてる？ちょっと…
Hey, are you even listening to me? Listen up now!
あ、それとね、白いおううまさん 決まってるでしょ？迎えに来て
Oh, and my white horse, you know what to do. Come and rescue me, it's up to you!
わかったらかしずいて手を取って「おひめさま」って
Once you know, bow down and take my hand, and call me your princess as planned!
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから でもね、少しぐらい叱ってくれたっていいのよ？
It's not like I'm being selfish, but scolding me a little is fine, you know?
世界でわたしだけのおうじさま 気が付いて ほらほら お手てが空いてます
My one and only prince in the world, notice me, look, my hand is empty, unfold!
世界で一番おひめさま
I'm the number one princess in the whole wide world
無口で無愛想なおうじさま
A silent and cold prince
もうどうして、気づいてよ早く
Why? Hurry up and notice!
ぜったいキミはわかってない！
You definitely don't understand!
わかってないわ……
You don't understand at all...
いちごの乗ったショートケーキ
Shortcake topped with strawberries
こだわりたまごのとろけるプリン
Melting pudding made with special eggs
みんなみんな我慢します
Everyone holds back
わがままな子だと思わないで
Don't think I'm just a selfish brat
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world
ちゃんと見ててよね どこかに行っちゃうよ
Watch me properly, or I'll go somewhere else
ふいに抱きしめられた
Suddenly I was hugged from behind...
急にそんな「危ないよ」なんて
Suddenly saying something like "It's dangerous"
そう言ってそっぽ向くキミ
You say that and look away
ねぇ 思い出の欠片に
Hey, if we put our memories
名前をつけて保存するなら
Into pieces and save them with names
宝物がぴったりだね
They'd be the perfect "treasure"
そう ココロの容量がいっぱいになるくらいに過ごしたね
We spent days that filled our hearts to the brim
ときめき色の毎日
Every day colored with excitement
なじんだ制服と上履き
Familiar uniforms and indoor shoes
ホワイトボードの落書き
Doodles on the whiteboard
明日の入り口に置いていかなくちゃいけないのかな
Do we have to leave them at tomorrow's entrance?
でもね、会えたよ！すてきな天使に
But hey, we met a wonderful angel!
卒業は終わりじゃない これからも仲間だから
Graduation isn't the end, we're friends from now on too
一緒の写真たち おそろいのキーホルダー
Photos together, matching keychains
いつでも輝いてる ずっと その笑顔 ありがとう
Shining forever, thank you for those smiles always
ねぇ 桜の木もちょっと 背が伸びたみたい
Hey, the cherry trees seem to have grown a bit taller
見えないゆっくりなスピードでも
Even at an invisible, slow speed
きっと あの空は見てたね
I'm sure that sky was watching
何度もつまずいたこと それでも最後まで歩けたこと
All the times we tripped, yet walked all the way to the end
ふわり 放課後の廊下に こぼれた音符の羽根
Gently fluttering down the after-school hallway, musical note feathers
ふかふか積もるまで このままでいられたいいのにな
I wish we could stay like this until they pile up fluffy
でもね、ふれたよ！愛すべき天使に
But hey, we were touched by a lovable angel!
ただいまっていいたくなる この場所は変わらないよ
This place where we want to say "I'm home" won't change
メールの受信箱 丸したカレンダー
Email inboxes, circled calendars
とびきりの夢と出会い くれた音楽に ありがとう
Thank you for the music that gave us such wonderful dreams
ねえ 思い出のカケラに 名前をつけて保存するなら
Hey, if I could name these memory fragments,
“宝物”がぴったりだね
calling them \"treasure\" fits best, right?
そう ココロの容量が いっぱいになるくらいに 過ごしたね とめきれ色の毎日
Yeah, we spent days so full our hearts overflowed with vibrant excitement.
ユニゾンで歌おう！
Let's sing in unison!
でもね、会えたよ！
But hey, I met you!
すてきな天使に
A wonderful angel!
卒業は終わりじゃない
Graduation isn't the end,
これからも仲間だから
we're still friends from here on out.
大好きって言うなら
If I say "I love you",
大大好きって返すよ
I'll reply with "I love you so much!"
忘れ物もうないよね
Nothing left behind, right?
ずっと永遠に一緒だよ
We'll be together forever!
ラストチャンスに飢えた爪先が
Starving for a final chance, my toes
踊り出すまま駆けけたこの夜空
dashed across this night sky as I danced on.
並のスタンスじゃナビかない
An ordinary stance won't get me through.
星は宝石の憧れ
Stars are the yearning of jewels,
浮かぶ涙と汗は血の名残り
floating tears and sweat are the remnants of blood.
目の中でしか泳げなきゃ芝居
If I can only swim in my eyes, it's just a play,
だけどステージが逃がさない
but the stage won't let me escape.
いついつまでも憧れ 焦がれているよ
Yearning forever and ever, I'm burning with desire.
I've never seen such a liar.
生まれつきだっての底なし
Bottomless since birth, you see.
This lie is love. And this lie is a gift to the world.
誰と生きたか思い出して
Remember who you lived with,
わたしが命を賭けるから あげるから
for I'll risk my life and give it to you!
あなたは時間をくれたのでしょう？
You gave me time, didn't you?
あらゆる望みの総てを叶えたら ああ果たせたら
If I could grant and fulfill every single desire, ah...
あなたに会いたい
I want to see you.
星に願いをかけて
Casting a wish upon the stars.
戻れないから大切にするの？
Do you cherish it because you can't go back?
始めないなら高をくくるよ
If you won't start, I'll take it lightly.
楽になる日はまず来ない
The day we find relief will never come first.
日々の中に集まる 悲しい光
A sorrowful light gathering within everyday life.
生まれつきだっての底なし
Bottomless since birth, you see.
This lie is love. And this lie is a gift to the world.
誰を生きたか忘れちゃった！
I forgot who I lived as!
あなたに命が戻るなら 届くなら
If life returns to you, if it reaches you,
わたしはどうなろうと構わないのに
I wouldn't care what happens to me...
どうやら総ては叶わない 叶わないならば
But it seems not all wishes come true; if they won't,
あなたになりたい 星は砕け光る
I want to become you. The stars shatter and shine.
わたしが命を賭けるから あげるから
For I'll risk my life and give it to you!
あなたは時間をくれたのでしょう？
You gave me time, didn't you?
あらゆる望みの総てを叶えたら ああ果たせたら
If I could grant and fulfill every single desire, ah...
あなたに会いたい
I want to see you.
星に願いをかけて
Casting a wish upon the stars.
さあ星の子たちよ よくお眠りなさい
Now, children of the stars, sleep soundly.
輝きは鈍らない あなたたちならば
If it's you, your radiance will never dull.
凍りついた心には太陽を
A sun for a frozen heart...
そして僕が君にとってそのポジションを
and to be in that position for you.
そんなだいぶ傲慢な思い込みをこじらせてたんだよ
I had such arrogant, warped assumptions stuck in my head.
ごめんね
I'm sorry.
笑ってやってよ
Please laugh it off.
火傷しそうなほどのポジティブの冷たさと残酷さに気付いたんだよ
I realized the coldness and cruelty of that burning positivity.
きっとな君に渡したいものは もっとひんやり熱いもの
Surely what I want to give you is something much cooler yet warmer.
綺麗事じゃないけど 綺麗で揺るぎないもの
It's not just talk, but something beautiful and unwavering.
うわべよりも 胸の奥の奥を温めるもの
Something that warms the very depths of your heart.
理想だけはあるけど 心のどこ探しても まるで見つからないんだよ
I have ideals, but no matter where I search, I just can't find them.
伝えたい 伝わらない その不条理が今
I want to convey it, but I can't—that irrationality now
キツく締め付けるんだよ
binds me tightly.
臆病な僕の この一挙手一投足を
Every little move of a coward like me...
言葉はまるで雪の結晶 君にプレゼントしたくても
Words are like snow crystals; even if I want to give them to you as a gift,
夢中になればなるほど 形は崩れ落ちて溶けていって 消えてしまうけど
the more absorbed I get, the more their shape collapses, melting and disappearing.
でも僕が選ぶ言葉が そこに託された想いが
But the words I choose, and the feelings entrusted in them,
君の胸を震わすのを 諦められない
cannot give up on making your heart tremble.
愛してるよりも愛が届くまで
Until my love reaches you, more than just saying "I love you,"
もう少しだけ待ってて
wait just a little longer.
薄着でただそばに立ってても 不必要に汗をかいてしまう僕なんかも
Even if I just stand by your side lightly clothed, a guy like me sweats unnecessarily.
どうしたって生ぬるくて 君を痛めつけてしまうのだろう
No matter what, it's lukewarm and probably ends up hurting you.
手のひらが熱いほど 心は冷たいんでしょう？
"The warmer your palms are, the colder your heart must be, right?"
冗談でもそんな残酷なこと言わないでよ
Don't say such cruel things, even as a joke.
別に言えばいいけど 全人生をかけても ちゃんと覆ささせてよ
You can say it if you want, but let me properly overturn it, even if I bet my whole life.
救いたい 救われたい このイコールが今 優しく剥がしていくんだよ
I want to save and be saved—this equation is now gently peeling away...
堅い理論武装 プライドの過剰包装
Stiff theoretical armor, excessive packaging of pride.
正しさよりも優しさが欲しい そしてそれを受け取れるのは
I want kindness rather than correctness, and the one who can receive it
イルミネーションみたいな 不特定多数じゃなくて ただ一人 君であってほしい
isn't an unspecified majority like illuminations, but just you, the one and only.
かけた言葉で割れた日々に直そうとして 足しすぎた熱量で 引かれてしまったカーテン
Trying to fix the days cracked by the words I said, with too much heat, the curtain was drawn.
そんな失敗作を 重ねて重ねて重ねて見つけたいんだいつか 最高の一句を
Over and over and over, stacking up such flawed works, I want to find someday the ultimate phrase.
言葉はまるで雪の結晶 君にプレゼントしたとして
Words are like snow crystals; even if I were to give them to you as a gift,
時間が経ってしまえば大抵 記憶からこぼれ落ちて溶けていって 消えてしまうけど
as time passes, they mostly spill from memory, melting and disappearing.
でも絶えず僕らのストーリーに 添えられた字幕のように
But like subtitles added continuously to our story,
思い返した時 不意に目をやる時に 君の胸を震わすもの
when looking back, when casting a sudden glance, something that vibrates your heart—
探し続けたい
I want to keep searching for it.
愛してるよりも愛が届くまで もう少しだけ待ってて
Until my love reaches you, more than just saying "I love you," wait just a little longer.
もう少しだけ
Just a little more,
just a little more,
踏み出せたのなら
if I could take a step forward.
言葉など何も欲しくないほど
So much so that I want no words at all,
悲しみに凍てつく夜でも
even on a night frozen with sadness,
勝手に君のそばで
arbitrarily by your side,
あれこれと考えてる
I'm thinking about this and that.
雪が溶けても 残ってる
Even when the snow melts, it remains.
色は匂えど 散りぬるを
Fragrant flowers bloom, only to scatter,
さ迷う事さえ 許せなかった…
I couldn't even forgive myself for wandering...
咲き誇る花はいつか
The flowers blooming in full glory
教えてくれた 生きるだけでは罪と
taught me one day that simply living is a sin,
離れられない 離せはしないと
that we are inseparable, and I will never let go.
抱く想いは 心を躍らせるばかり
The feelings I hold only make my heart dance.
色は匂えど 散りぬるを
Fragrant flowers bloom, only to scatter,
さ迷う暇はないけれど
there's no time to wander, yet stepping back,
甘えるか弱さと 甘えれぬ弱さで
with fragile weakness or unyielding weakness,
悪夢が優しく 私を弄ぶ
nightmares gently toy with me.
弱さ知るアナタは今
You, who know weakness, right now
許してくれた 求める者の欲を
forgave the desires of those who seek.
健気に咲いた 刹那の美しさを
The transient beauty of a flower blooming bravely—
それを知るには 遅すぎたのかもしれない…
perhaps it was too late to realize it...
色は匂えど 散りぬるを
Fragrant flowers bloom, only to scatter,
アナタのすべてに 幼く委ねたい…
I want to childishly entrust myself to all of you...
許せぬ優しさと 揺るぐ独占欲は
Unforgivable gentleness and wavering possessiveness
秤にかけれぬ 我儘な愛
cannot be weighed: a selfish love.
色は匂えど すべて散りぬるを
Fragrant flowers bloom, and all scatter away,
短き記憶に 溢れる想い
feelings overflowing in a short-lived memory.
枯れゆく命よ 儚く強くあれ
Oh withering life, be fleeting yet strong,
無慈悲で優しい 時のように
like a time both merciless and gentle.
Blessings for your birthday
Blessings for your everyday
剥がしてもなぜだか 増えてくタクト
Even when peeled off, for some reason batons multiply,
ランク付けされてく 理不尽な価値
unreasonable values assigned with rankings.
Blessings for your birthday
Blessings for your everyday
最後の一秒まで前を向け
Face forward until the very last second
剥がしても何故か増えてくタグと
With tags that multiply even if torn off
ランク付けされてく理不尽な価値
And the unreasonable worth from the rank attached to you
そんな数値で人を推し量らないでと
You shouldn't make assumptions about people with those values
飛び交う言葉を手で覆い隠した
I masked those fluttering words with my hands
Oh... It's time to get up 灯火を消す前に
Oh, it's time to get up, before you turn off the light
Oh... It's time to get up 足元を照らせ!
Oh, it's time to get up, brighten your step!
ほら ここを じっと 見つめて みて
Hey, try to take a good look over here
最高の 味方が 映ってる でしょ?
Your greatest ally is reflected back at you, right?
それは 命の証
That's the proof of life
Blessings for your birthday
Blessings for your everyday
例え 明日世界が 滅びても
Even if the world is in ruins tomorrow
Blessings for your birthday
Blessings for your everyday
最後の一秒まで 前を向け
Face forward until the very last second
Hip hip HOORAY これから 先も
From here onwards, hip, hip, hooray
Hip hip HOORAY 君に 幸あれ
All the best to you, hip, hip, hooray
ゼロ から イチ を 生むのは 容易くない事
It's not easy to make something from nothing
肝心な物は 見えないし 触れない事
The important things are the ones you can't see or touch
不幸とは 幸せだと 気づけない事
Unhappiness is when you can't grasp that you're happy
毎日が 誕生日で 命日の事
Live everyday as if it's your birthday and your last day
Oh... Stand up take action 泥沼を掻き分けて
Oh, stand up, take action, push your way through the mud
Oh... Stand up take action 蓮の花は咲く!
Oh, stand up, take action, and the lotus flowers will bloom!
ほら ここに 手を重ねて みて
Hey, try to place your hand on top of mine here
温もりが 伝わってくる でしょ?
You can feel the warmth, right?
それは 命の証
That's the proof of life
Blessings for your birthday
Blessings for your everyday
例え 綺麗事だって 構わない
Even if it's a challenge, it doesn't matter
Blessings for your birthday
Blessings for your everyday
この世に 生まれてきてくれて ありがとう
Thank you for being born into this world
Hip hip HOORAY これから 先も
From here onwards, hip, hip, hooray
Hip hip HOORAY 君に 幸あれ
All the best to you, hip, hip, hooray
さあ さ 近寄って
Hurry! Step right this way
ラッシャイ 見て
Come on and see
ラッシャイ
Welcome
ロック で いっ たら こんな 風
If you say it in a rock style, it's like this
like this x 2 yeah
Like this, like this, yeah
アカペラ で いっ たら こんな 風
If you say it in an acapella style, it's like this
like this x 2 yeah
Like this, like this, yeah
ゲーム で いっ たら こんな 風
If you say it in a game style, it's like this
like this x 2 yeah
Like this, like this, yeah
ダンス で いっ たら こんな 風
If you say it in a dance style, it's like this
da da da da da
よく 食べ て
Eat well
よく 眠っ て
Sleep well
よく 遊ん で
Play well
よく 学ん で
Learn well
よく 喋っ て
Speak well
よく 喧嘩 し て
Fight well
ごく 普通な 毎日 を
Living quite a normal everyday
泣け なく て も
Even if you can't cry
笑え なく て も
Even if you can't laugh
歌え なく て も
Even if you can't sing
何 も なく て も
Even if you've got nothing
愛せ なく て も
Even if you can't love
愛さ れ なく て も
Even if you aren't loved
それでも 生き て 欲しい
Even then, I want you to live
Blessings for your birthday
Blessings for your everyday
例え 明日世界が 滅びても
Even if the world is in ruins tomorrow
Blessings for your birthday
Blessings for your everyday
最後の一秒まで 前を向け
Face forward until the very last second
if you're alive あの子が 振り向く かも
If you're alive, that person might turn around
if you're alive 宝くじ 当たる かも
If you're alive, you might win the lottery
if you're alive 再び 始まる かも
If you're alive, it might begin again
生き抜く ため なら
If it's for the sake of living on
棒に振れ
Go ahead and waste
水を差す
Interrupt
煙に巻く
Confuse
油を売れ
Disturb
現を抜かせ
and obsess
そして 来週も 来月も 来年も 来世も 一緒に 祝おう
And next week, next month, next year, and the next life, let's celebrate together
Blessings for your birthday
Blessings for your everyday
例え 綺麗事だって 構わない
Even if it's a challenge, it doesn't matter
Blessings for your birthday
Blessings for your everyday
ここに 集めた 奇跡に ありがとう
Thank you for bringing us all together here
Hip hip HOORAY これから 先も
From here onwards, hip, hip, hooray
Hip hip HOORAY 君に 幸あれ
All the best to you, hip, hip, hooray
Hip hip HOORAY これから 先も
From here onwards, hip, hip, hooray
Hip hip HOORAY 君に 幸あれ
All the best to you, hip, hip, hooray
Hip hip HOORAY これから 先も
From here onwards, hip, hip, hooray
Hip hip HOORAY 君に 幸あれ
All the best to you, hip, hip, hooray
Hip hip HOORAY これから 先も
From here onwards, hip, hip, hooray
Hip hip HOORAY 君に 幸あれ
All the best to you, hip, hip, hooray
Blessings for your birthday
Blessings for your everyday
例え 明日世界が 滅びても
Even if the world is in ruins tomorrow
Blessings for your birthday
Blessings for your everyday
最後の一秒まで 前を向け
Face forward until the very last second
Blessings for your birthday
Blessings for your everyday
例え 綺麗事だって 構わない
Even if it's a challenge, it doesn't matter
Blessings for your birthday
Blessings for your everyday
ここに 集めた 奇跡に ありがとう
Thank you for bringing us all together here
Hip hip HOORAY これから 先も
From here onwards, hip, hip, hooray
Hip hip HOORAY 君に 幸あれ
All the best to you, hip, hip, hooray
Hip hip HOORAY
はーい、というわけで、ここまで来てくれたみんな、ありがとう！
Hi there! So, thank you everyone for coming this far!
この後もう少しだけ続くし、最後に告知もありますが
There's a little bit more after this, and some announcements at the end,
今からみんなおまちかね、紫咲シオン誕生日記念2023年グッズの紹介です！
but right now, what everyone's been waiting for: the introduction of Murasaki Shion's 2023 Birthday Commemorative Goods!
いやあ、今回もね、めっちゃいいのこだわって作っちゃったので、一つ一つ紹介していきたいと思います！
Man, this time too, I put a lot of care into making really great items, so I'd like to introduce them one by one!
えー、誕生日記念フルセットはこんな感じです。
Umm, the Birthday Commemorative Full Set looks like this.
いやもうこれ見ただけでね、もうね、うわこれ気になる、早く早くってね、ちょっとおもってると思うんですけど
Man, just looking at this, you're probably thinking, "Woah, I'm curious about this, hurry up!" right?
まあ、ゆっくり待ってくださいよ！というわけで、まず第1、
Well, wait slowly! So, first of all,
ふわもふあったかブランケット！もうね、イラストがマジで可愛い、もうね、マジで可愛い！服装もね
the Fluffy Warm Blanket! The illustration is seriously so cute, seriously so cute! The outfit too,
ちょっとあの部屋着っぽい感じになっておりますね。ブランケットということで
is in a bit of room-wear style. And as a blanket,
フェルト生地とかではなくて、ちゃんとうわふぁしてる、
Not made of felt, but fluffy,
あったかいふわふわもふもふした感じの生地になってます。
a warm, fluffy, and cozy fabric.
あのちゃんとね肌触りがね、いい感じになってるので、
It has a really nice texture, so
いやぜひこれマジで使ってほしいです。
I really want you to use this.
本当にいいのでお勧め！
It's genuinely great, highly recommended!
次、ぐっすりアイマスク。
Next up, the Sound Sleep Eye Mask.
いやあね、塩っ子になってますね。
Yeah, it turns you into a Shiokko.
これ塩っ子になれますからね、これみんな付けたらね、
You can become a Shiokko if everyone wears it,
あの目にね、目が顔が塩っ子になれるのでね、
your face can become Shiokko... haha!
これね、リボンが付いてるんですが、
This has a ribbon attached, and
リボンもちゃんと立体感でちょっとぷっくりした感じのね、立体感のあるデザインで、
the ribbon has a nice 3D, plump design with
あの目とかね刺繍になっております。
embroidered eyes and details.
めちゃ可愛いし、
It's super cute, and
あのほかほか、ちゃんと付け心地めちゃいいのにしたので、
we made sure the fit is super comfortable,
ちょっとちゃんとね目、目にねあの痛くない、ふぁっとした感じの質感になっているので、
so it feels soft and gentle on your eyes without hurting,
これを使って、みんな寝てください毎夜。
please use this to sleep every night.
いやこれめっちゃいいよ。
Seriously, it's amazing.
次、もちもち塩っ子ぬいぐるみ。
Next, the Mochi-Mochi Shiokko Plushie.
あのね、これがね、ほんとにね、これ抱っこして寝て欲しいんだよね、みんなに。
Um, this, seriously... I want everyone to hold this and sleep.
いや、これ今回はちょっとみんながのゆっくり安眠できるグッズにしようと思って、
This time, I wanted to make goods that help everyone sleep soundly,
これね、もちもちしてるんだよ。
and this is super squishy.
触り心地がめちゃ良くて、もちもちしてて、
The texture is amazing, super squishy,
なでれる。なでるとふかふかしてる。本当にいい感じなのでね、
and you can pet it. Petting it makes it fluffy. It feels so good,
あのぜひこれを抱いて寝て欲しいですね、皆様には。はい。
so I really want you all to sleep hugging this. Yeah.
次、えこれはちょっと作りたくて作りました。
Next up, I really wanted to make this.
たくさんしゃべる！？ボイスキーホルダー！
The "Talks a Lot!?" Voice Keychain!
なんとね6種類のボイスが入っていて、
It features 6 different voice lines,
いやこれはですね、過去の配信でみんなにね、言ってほしいセリフを募集した時に来た、
and when I asked for lines you wanted me to say in past streams,
結構変なセリフが多かったんですけど、ちゃんとねみんなの要望にも答えれてると思う。本当に！
there were quite a few weird ones, but I think it really answers everyone's requests. Truly!
いやこれぜひ聞いてください。みんなの要望が叶うと思って聞いてください。はい取り入れておりますので。
So please listen to it believing your wishes will come true. Yes, we've incorporated them.
ね、デザインもめちゃ可愛いんですよね。なもり先生が描いてくれたんですけど、
The design is also super cute. Namori-sensei drew it for us,
押すとね、しゃべるので、ぜひカバンとかにつけて、毎朝押してください。
and it speaks when you press it, so attach it to your bag and press it every morning!
最後に記念ボイス！これはあの有料のボイスになっております。
Lastly, the Commemorative Voice! This is a paid voice pack.
あの全部買った方にはついてきますね、全部セットにも含まれております。
It comes with the full set if you purchase everything.
シチュエーションボイス「ねむねむシオンちゃん」ということで、
The situational voice is "Sleepy Shion-chan",
これはあの、お昼寝、テーマがお昼寝になっております。ぜひ聞いてください。
and the theme is napping. Please give it a listen.
ちょっと恥ずかしいですけど、ぜひ気になる人は聞いてください。
It's a bit embarrassing, but please check it out if you're curious.
最後にフルセット購入特典はこちらです。
Lastly, here is the full set purchase bonus.
イラストがね、さっき紹介しそびれちゃったんですけど、さくらしおり先生のキラキラしたかわいいね、
The illustration—I forgot to introduce it earlier—is a sparkly, cute one by Sakura Shiori-sensei,
今回サブンでね、フードなしのポストカードになっております。
featuring a hooded-less postcard this time.
これもめちゃ可愛いですよね。
This is also super cute, right?
あの複製サインと、今回限定のメッセージが入っております。複製のメッセージが入っております。
It includes a replica signature and a limited-edition message.
どういてからののお楽しみということで、ぜひ記念セットね、フルセットで買ってもらえたらなと思います。
It's a surprise for after it arrives, so I hope you'll buy the commemorative full set.
というわけで、いやいかがだったでしょうか。
So, how did you like them?
個人的にはめちゃくちゃこだわったグッズなので、みんなの手元に渡ったらとても嬉しいなと思っております。
Personally, I'm very particular about these goods, so I'd be so happy if they reach everyone.
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you for your support.
この後もまだもう少しだけ続くのでね、最後まで目を離さずに告知もありますのでよろしくお願いします。
There's still a little more to come, including announcements, so please keep watching until the end.
それではこの後も楽しんでってね！
Well then, please continue to enjoy the rest!
さあ ごらんあれ 君のシンデレラ
Now behold, your Cinderella
今宵も始めよう
Let's begin tonight as well
Shall we dance?
おとぎ話の主人公 いつも鏡の中で夢見てる
Protagonist of a fairytale, always dreaming inside the mirror
弱音だらけの私でも 画面の中では強くありたいんだけど
Even with all my complaints, I want to be strong inside the screen, but
強がり 怖がり 寂しがり 弱虫 言われてばっかりで 思い出す度に震える声
Acting tough, being scared, lonely, always called a coward, my voice trembles whenever I remember
なんて そんなの嘘っぱちだから 信じて私だけを見て
As if! That's all nonsense, so believe in me and look only at me
反撃開始のドレスを着て 魔法が解ける前に
Wearing the dress to start our counterattack, before the magic wears off
さあ ごらんあれ 君のシンデレラ
Now behold, your Cinderella
ガラスの靴履いて 可愛く映ってますか？
Wearing glass slippers, do I look cute?
高らかに踊って見せよう
Let's dance proudly and show them
これが私なんだ
This is who I am
Shall we dance?
「所詮は」だなんて分かったふりして 口から出まかせで
Pretending to understand with things like "after all", just talking nonsense
「ホントは」だなんて甘過ぎ？軽蔑痴話 言いたくないんだって もぉ…
"Too sweet to say 'the truth'? Such mocking foolishness... I don't want to say it, mhm..."
ノイズを無視して 全部笑い飛ばして
Ignoring the noise, laughing it all away,
不安拭って 立ち止まるな
wiping away the anxiety, don't stop.
そらさないで強くさせて アン ドゥ トロワ
Don't look away, let me be strong. Un, deux, trois!
0時を回っても 逃げずに戦っているの
Even past midnight, I'm fighting without running away.
気高く綺麗に舞い上がって
Soaring high, noble and beautiful.
泣いてる暇なんかない
There's no time to be crying.
「タラレバ」なんかじゃなく 「これから」を生きたいの
Not living in "what-ifs," but wanting to live for "what's ahead."
反撃開始のドレスを着て 魔法解ける前に
Wearing the dress of counterattack before the magic wears off.
さあご覧あれ 君のシンデレラ アン ドゥ トロワ
Now behold, your Cinderella. Un, deux, trois!
ガラスの靴履いて 可愛く映ってますか？
Wearing glass slippers, do I look cute?
誇らしげに踊ってみせよう
Let me show you how proudly I can dance.
これが私なんだ shall we dance! ねっ？ ah...
This is who I am. Shall we dance? Right? Ah...
誇らしげに踊ってみせよう
Let me show you how proudly I can dance.
もっと shall we dance! ねっ？
Even more! Shall we dance? Right?
みんな見てくれてありがとう！
Thank you everyone for watching!
そして告知があります。このあとすぐの21時から「シンデレラ・マジック」のMVがプレミア公開されます！
And I have an announcement. Right after this at 21:00, the premiere of the "Cinderella Magic" MV will go live!
本当にこだわって作ったMVなので、本当にイラストもね何十枚もあって見ていて楽しいMVとなっていると思うので、みんなに絶対見てほしいです！
We put a lot of care into making this MV, with dozens of illustrations to enjoy, so I really want everyone to watch it!
約束！それじゃあちゃんと見てね！バイバーイ！
Promise! So make sure to watch it properly! Bye-bye!